

# lan Clark A. Villegas

# Junior Developer

# Contact

Address

Cebu City, Cebu. Philippines 6000

Phone

+639932696842

Mail

clarkvillegas2021@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ia

n-clark-villegas-391

Website

https://ian-villegas-portfolio.n etlifv.app/

# Technical Profile

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Typescript

SQL

MySQL

Bootstrap MongoDB React Postman

# **Personal Summary**

With almost five years of experience as a novice full stack web developer, I offer a strong foundation in front-end and back-end programming along with a mix of excitement and curiosity. I've been deeply involved with a variety of technologies and frameworks over the last few years, happily embracing new challenges and educational opportunities as I go. And maintain full-time position that offers professional challenges utilizing interpersonal skills. excellent time management problem-solving skills. Willingness take added responsibilities to meet team goals.

#### Work Experience

### Five64 LLC

February 2021 -June 2023

(Freelance)

# **Quality Assurance**

- >Supported test review, defect control and configuration management within delivery pipeline.
- >Collaborated with product owners to stay current on intended functionality.
- Identified and tracked defects with PostMan and supported developers with resolution tactics.
- >Optimized test cases to maximize success of manual software testing.
- >Coordinated work with various teams to solve problems and improve efficiency for software testing and automation.
- >Assisted team with development of web-based applications in Agile environment.
- >Collaborated with QA team to test software quality through manual and automated testing.
- >Defined and identified test cases for new application development.

#### Inchcape

# February 2023 - July 2023 (Freelance)

### Front End Developer

- >Working closely with designers to ensure the correct implementation of UI components, layouts and visuals
- >Troubleshooting layout and functional issues across multiple browsers and devices.
- >Implementing and maintaining scalable front-end architecture utilizing latest JavaScript libraries, Typescript and React frameworks
- >Building reusable code that is scalable and optimized for performance.
- >Implementing web accessibility standards and developing suitable web content for all browsers, platforms, and devices.
- >Developing user-friendly web pages and features to effectively optimize user experience.
- >Utilizing industry best practices for mobile-first and responsive web design.

# Ian Clark A. Villegas Junior Developer

# Competencies

**HTML Experties** 

CSS Proficiency

JavaScript Programming

MySQL Proficiency

NodeJS Proficiency

React Proficiency

Typescript Proficiency

Debugging

Teamwork and Collaboration

**Test Planning** 

#### Work Experience

#### Tekion Global

June 2023 - November 2024 (Full-time)

## **Quality Assurance Engineer**

>Implementing and maintaining scalable front-end architecture utilizing latest JavaScript libraries, Typescript and React frameworks >Building reusable code that is scalable and optimized for performance.

- >Implementing web accessibility standards and developing suitable web content for all browsers, platforms, and devices.
- >Developing user-friendly web pages and features to effectively optimize user experience
- >Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver on-time and on-budget projects and initiatives.
- >Supported test review, defect control and configuration management within delivery pipeline.
- >Collaborated with product owners to stay current on intended functionality.
- >Identified and tracked defects with PostMan and supported developers with resolution tactics.
- >Optimized test cases to maximize success of manual software testing.
- >Coordinated work with various teams to solve problems and improve efficiency for software testing and automation.
- >Assisted team with development of web-based applications in Agile environment.
- >Collaborated with QA team to test software quality through manual and automated testing.
- >Defined and identified test cases for new application development.

# Education Experience

Certification: Computer Programming

Full Stack Web Developer Certificate

Zuitt Bootcamp - Caswynn Building, 3<sup>rd</sup> Floor, 134 Timog Eve, Quezon

**Bachelor of Science: Electrical Engineering** 

Undergraduate - 4th year College

Cebu Institute of Technology - Universities - N. Bacalso Ave, Cebu City

**High School Diploma** 

Madridejos National High School - Madridejos Cebu City